<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Silviu Tantos (razius)</title><link href="http://razius.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/toughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://razius.com/</id><updated>2013-10-14T19:14:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Move fast and break things</title><link href="http://razius.com/articles/move-fast-and-break-things/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-14T19:14:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Silviu Tantos</name></author><id>tag:razius.com,2013-10-14:articles/move-fast-and-break-things/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move fast and break things&lt;/em&gt; is one of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LPSbtqGiol4"&gt;founding mantras&lt;/a&gt; of Facebook and I think it defines a company culture that can apply to almost any technology startup. It is a culture who&amp;#8217;s principles embody, promote and encourage communication, constant and fast iterations, tight feedback loop between the implementation and the design, short code-to-deployment cycles, experimentation and&amp;nbsp;efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are also just a few of the reasons why I chose to be a part of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.iconfinder.com/"&gt;Iconfinder&lt;/a&gt; team and to do my internship at a startup company instead
of a traditional one. I have the perfect environment for rapid professional growth, I can acquire new skills and sharpen my old ones at a much faster pace, I feel challenged everyday and I have the pleasure of working with the newest&amp;nbsp;technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;em&gt;move fast and break things&lt;/em&gt; culture the &lt;em&gt;break things&lt;/em&gt;, as I&amp;#8217;ve come to find out, is not optional. To continue to improve you have to make mistakes from which you have to learn and my recent blunder is one of those mistakes. During the development of the new comment section a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.iconfinder.com/cookie-hijacking/"&gt;serious bug&lt;/a&gt; slipped through making it possible for attackers to hijack cookies from users. The bug was discovered and fixed under 2 hours and didn&amp;#8217;t have any major repercussions apart from the inconvenience of clearing the session storage and having all users log in&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve learned a lot this month, some lessons where learned the hard way, from mistakes, but it&amp;#8217;s been a fun ride so far and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to see what the future will&amp;nbsp;bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some geeky&amp;nbsp;statistics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git commits:&amp;nbsp;101&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git code line additions: 4.674&amp;nbsp;++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git code line deletions: 1.430&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8212;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee cups consumed:&amp;nbsp;82&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of times I caused chaos:&amp;nbsp;1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minutes wishing I was somewhere else:&amp;nbsp;0.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of tasks accomplished so&amp;nbsp;far:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://razius.com/2013/09/vagrant-and-ssh-agent-forwarding/"&gt;Vagrant machine&lt;/a&gt; to use for local&amp;nbsp;development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a PayPal cash out&amp;nbsp;option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented a new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.iconfinder.com/iconsets/20-flat-icons"&gt;comment section&lt;/a&gt;, replacing&amp;nbsp;Disqus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a Python script to generate a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/178636?hl=en"&gt;image sitemap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated internal notifications into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.hipchat.com/"&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt;, our internal
communication&amp;nbsp;application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did various &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; and Javascript&amp;nbsp;fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="iconfinder"></category><category term="internship"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Copenhagen and my r’bad_luck’</title><link href="http://razius.com/articles/copenhagen-and-my-rbad_luck/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-08T11:46:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Silviu Tantos</name></author><id>tag:razius.com,2013-09-08:articles/copenhagen-and-my-rbad_luck/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To tell you the story of my string of bad luck and my first week of
internship in Copenhagen, I&amp;#8217;ll first have to start with my last week. It
was Saturday, the day before I had to leave for Copenhagen, I was there
minding my own business, when my laptop suddenly decided that he is
thirsty. Now, my laptop being a laptop and having no hands, couldn&amp;#8217;t
achieve this feat by&amp;nbsp;itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter me and my clumsy hands. In my infinite star gazing mode, I knock
down a glass of water down on my laptop, helping him quenching his
thirst and in the same time helping him commit&amp;nbsp;suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter me in panic mode. There I was on a Saturday evening without a
laptop and I would have to start work on Monday. Luckily I managed to
borrow an older laptop from somebody I know but only on Sunday evening,
leaving me with little time to swap it&amp;#8217;s hard-drive with the hard-drive
from my old laptop and to try to boot my old Linux installation from it.
If I managed to get it to boot it I would at least have all my files and
could work properly. But the laptop that I borrowed, being as stubborn
as a wild stallion being caught and trained, decided to all of a sudden
defy me and refuse to boot my Linux installation&amp;nbsp;properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of hours of intense training I tamed him and manage to
boot my Linux installation successfully. I was finally presented with a
beautiful login screen with my name on&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward Friday evening. The end of my first internship week. After
an office party I head down to Copenhagen Central Station at around 2 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;
to take the train back to Horsens to sleep at a friend for the weekend
and to take my things back to Copenhagen. Having still a couple of hours
till the train arrives I sit on a bench and put my backpack in between
my legs. After a couple of minutes I start to doze off. Upon waking up I
realize that my backpack with all my things is gone, somebody stole it
in the meantime. I had my laptop with all my data, phone, id, credit
card and my ticket back to Horsens in&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, at this point, I have to mention that I also didn&amp;#8217;t have a place to
stay in Copenhagen. When leaving for Copenhagen I didn&amp;#8217;t find anything
to rent so I just lived in a hostel for the past 5 days with the plan of
returning to Horsens for the weekend. I packed just enough clothes for
the week and my intention was to go back to Horsens for the weekend and
return on Sunday when the apartment that I finally manage to rent would
be&amp;nbsp;available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So exit scene for now, it&amp;#8217;s Friday night (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;3AM&lt;/span&gt;), I&amp;#8217;m standing in the
middle of Copenhagen Central Station, with my hands on top of my head,
philosophizing on universe&amp;#8217;s strange idea of humor. I am without a place
to stay, without a way to contact somebody, without knowing anybody or
anyplace and without a way to at least get back to Horsens. Everything I
have on me are a couple of beer&amp;nbsp;caps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="copenhagen"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>About stuff</title><link href="http://razius.com/articles/about-stuff/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-31T19:53:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Silviu Tantos</name></author><id>tag:razius.com,2013-07-31:articles/about-stuff/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I moved to Denmark, from my home country Romania, exactly two years ago to the day with just a small suitcase and a backpack. In them I had a hand-full of clothes, a few personal belongings and my&amp;nbsp;laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the past couple of years things started to accumulate, I started buying new things, some out of necessity others because I wanted&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="My luggage when moving to Denmark" src="http://razius.com/images/articles/moving-to-denmark.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My luggage when moving to Horsens,&amp;nbsp;Denmark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fortunately because as a student I had limited space and resources I was forced in a certain mindset, making me think twice before buying something. For example when I needed something, I tried to buy the cheapest thing that would serve it&amp;#8217;s purpose, I bought a computer chair and a table for 5$, a bed for 50$ and a lamp for 2$. Being cheap, when moving out instead of taking them with me I could just leave them behind,less thing to move, less hassle and effort spent on moving them&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being accepted for an internship in Copenhagen and facing the possibility of living in a hostel for an undetermined period of time made me decide to see how much I could slim down my list of possessions again. My objective was simple, everything that I own should fit in my backpack and my travel bag (or less if&amp;nbsp;possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I end up&amp;nbsp;with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="My luggage when moving to Denmark" src="http://razius.com/images/articles/moving-to-copenhagen.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Everything I currently&amp;nbsp;own&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clothes&lt;/strong&gt;, nothing spectacular&amp;nbsp;here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two pairs of shoes&lt;/strong&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve always owned no more than 2-3 pair, never felt like I needed&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinkpad T500&lt;/strong&gt; laptop +&amp;nbsp;mouse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle&lt;/strong&gt; which I find incredibly useful, it allows me to carry tons of books around with little physical space requirements. I would love to own physical books, but it feels like they would be too much of a hassle right&amp;nbsp;now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External hard-drive&lt;/strong&gt; to back-up the data from my&amp;nbsp;laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTC&lt;/span&gt; One S phone&lt;/strong&gt;, it also acts as my camera, alarm clock and whatever other uses I can think&amp;nbsp;of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPod Touch&lt;/strong&gt;, I bought it to develop and test a iOS application. I&amp;#8217;m considering selling it and buying a proper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Longboard&lt;/strong&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve bought this one last year and I consider it incredibly&amp;nbsp;fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ogio backpack&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not shown in the&amp;nbsp;picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charger and a docking station for the&amp;nbsp;laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pair of headphones,a usb cable for my phone/iPod/Kindle and one for my external&amp;nbsp;hard-drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer that I keep back home in Romania which is acting as an off-site back-up server for my files, every night the content of my laptop is saved on to it. In this way if anything happens to my laptop or the data on it, I would still have what&amp;#8217;s most important, my files and&amp;nbsp;data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A shoe box filled with personal&amp;nbsp;memories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m gonna leave you with a great comedy sketch by George Carlin and an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://storyofstuff.org/"&gt;awesome website&lt;/a&gt; on the&amp;nbsp;subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ERROR&lt;/span&gt;/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/media/storage/workspace/projects/razius.github.io/content/articles/toughts/about-stuff.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line&amp;nbsp;46)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unknown directive type&amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;youtube&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
.. youtube:: MvgN5gCuLac

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="stuff"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello world!</title><link href="http://razius.com/articles/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-15T09:52:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Silviu Tantos</name></author><id>tag:razius.com,2011-08-15:articles/hello-world/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much slacking around and ignoring this blog I decided to give it another spin and bring it back to&amp;nbsp;life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be mostly technical articles about Linux, system administration and network&amp;nbsp;administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="codehilitetable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;root@crappy:/# &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;Hello, World!&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
Hello, World!
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category></entry></feed>